i know you're probably sick of hearing
all of these plugs all the time but
there really is only one more day to get
your hands on a pesky bird t-shirt a
grain or even a barge t-shirt the link
is in the description let's get on with
the episode so the big news to start off
our episode is we have got this space
cleared so massive thank you to hypno
and impulse for not only selling up but
actually moving the shops i was more
than willing to do it but look at this
we've got ourselves
a pretty decent space that all we have
to do now is clear and figure out what
we're gonna do and my next challenge is
to protest this tree getting removed
need a petition so i'm gonna remove all
of this stuff but there's actually
something way more important than the
barge wow i never thought i'd say that
yeah there is something a little bit
more important than the barge right now
because we want to square away
the turf war the grass versus mycelium
and
everyone needs somewhere to make their
mini game so as i said in last episode
i need to create a nice space for it and
you can see i've i've started because
there's a mess
so this is by far way more important
because without this people can't start
their mini game so it's really on me to
get this going
so that's what we're gonna do at the
start of today's episode it's gonna be a
bit of a grind don't get me wrong i i
know how this is gonna go this is not a
small area this is a lot of water
but i'm dedicated and everyone is
relying on me so that we can get this
done all right so
i mean i know that's a pretty swift
intro but let's get straight into
terraforming this land
[Music]
this took a surprising amount of time
and don't worry it's going to be much
prettier than this but i had a pretty
interesting idea on how to cover this
half grass and half mycelium and maybe
we can use this as a bit of a prediction
of fate if you will so what i'm gonna do
and try and keep this as fair as
possible on this side i'm gonna place
low a line of mycelium all the way along
here
and then on the other side i'm gonna do
a line of grass and we're gonna see
which one beats it in a
probably the slowest race in history so
we're gonna see what happens so let's
load up the mycelium and i know that my
ceiling will get a slight head start but
i think in the grand scheme of things
it's going to take hours for this thing
to spread and probably won't make a huge
difference to the overall outcome but in
theory
they should reach the middle
together right quickly we go to the
other side and do grass unfortunately in
a mesa biome the grass is not gonna look
very good as you can see it's quite dark
and just so it can be a bit more of a
fair experiment i'm gonna replace some
of these head start mycelium so there we
go now all we have to do is watch the
slowest battle ever
[Music]
can't believe i just spent like two
hours watching grass grow
in my little cubby hole here but check
it out
grass
and mycelium and a mini game is already
in creation
what is that what do you reckon that is
guys that looks like some sort of
football game but then there's a bit in
the i'm not sure looks interesting
though but i must admit now that there
is a small mini game right there
it makes this area look a lot
smaller than i initially thought
so i thought this was going to be
massive way too big for what we actually
needed this to be it looks like mycelium
might have pulled just over the halfway
line
but i don't know i'm not entirely sure
if it has either way it has produced the
results that i wanted now i have to
admit this area is extremely ugly at the
moment but me and scar are gonna work
together to try and make this look a
little more pretty our main concern was
getting a flat area ready so that people
can actually start making their mini
games that was the goal so let's talk
about my mini games i have two ideas for
minigames and i don't know which one to
do so i'm gonna let you decide because
the first idea actually requires next to
no
input from me it's called kill green
so basically one member of hep and one
member of the resistance
have to go head to head
and kill me
but it's not like a pvp battle no no no
no no they have to get as creative as
possible so they could they could just
turn up and kill me with a sword but
that wouldn't be very surprising would
it so the idea is they have to get
creative create a machine or a trap or
something that takes me by surprise or
it doesn't have to take me by surprise
they could set something up here in
the turf war battleground i could set
like an area up and say create a machine
in here that kills me or kill me by
surprise so that's option one kill green
see i i like this idea but the downside
of this idea is that i don't actually
have to do any work you see i don't
actually have to set anything up other
than some signs explaining my minigame
idea number two is a skydiving minigame
so what i would do is essentially create
a skydiving course of some kind and
build a plane all the way up in the sky
you have to jump off it
and fly down and make your way into
all that happens oh thank goodness the
spawn is nearby wow that looks pretty so
yeah i mean i just
i just demonstrated what happens if you
don't do but the idea is there'll be a
plane in the sky
you skydive downwards and you have to
skydive you both jump at the same time
you've got to go through the rings as
you go down
and it will be a points based system man
this is a really long swim but kind of
therapeutic at sunset don't you think
sploosh
[Laughter]
mumbo's just seen my embarrassing swim
this is the swim of shame i'm shame
swimming don't take my stuff ah dude i
had so many levels is he just
what is he doing i'm right here mumbo he
uh he did not just you did not just save
me although i could use saving right now
i'm missing quite a lot of stuff mumbo
he just stole my rocket
mumbo's just made off with some of my
stuff holy moly that is an army my bed
cubby hole was not good for respawning
in and i could kind of see why okay so
you get the idea there will be different
sized holes here
and it will all be point dependent so
here's the thing you've got to start
up in the sky
like this
you start on an airplane and then you've
got to dive down and i need to figure
out a few things but come on i can do it
no come on i actually bounced in the
water
i'm starting to think that mumbo it's
okay
i'm kind of embarrassing myself in front
of mumbo now where are my boots where
are my boots for my tootsies there they
are okay so one last chance you go up to
the airplane
and you've got to dive down
and land
in
the hole i'm not gonna make it am i
oh
i promise i've done this before
watch this oh he's not gonna try it is
he
he's not gonna try it
oh no
that's like the equivalent mum mum mum
watch this mum watch this mum watch this
i've started to think my mini game might
not end well for anyone
i don't even know where my stuff is now
right we're going to take off our armor
and we're just going to have elijah and
rockets i've got to prove to myself that
this is possible
right
fourth time fifth time lucky you go up
into the airplane
you jump and you've got to fly through
hoops
and then you gotta
no come on i made it through that my
body made it through the hole i'm gonna
keep trying until i get this
okay jumping off flying through hoops
flying through hoops
to be honest i think we can probably
just call both of these games kill green
right here we go we've got to line this
up properly but it's got to be a skype
no i'm not even close i feel it it's not
not lined up properly this is the one i
feel it
oh come on
let's take a little look at chat shall
we
everything is fine at some point i do
have to give up but today is not that
day
ah should have bailed mumbo's just
watching me we will get this
we'll feel good about this one
yes
he's gonna do it is he gonna do it is he
gonna do it
point proven it can be done it just
takes 20 minutes at a time so
you know what after doing that multiple
times i realized that the the skydiving
mini game is actually way more fun it's
probably going to be more of a spectacle
and i don't know i i feel like everyone
can then try a skydive yeah you know
what you guys don't get to choose i
changed my mind unless i see a million
comments saying that they'd prefer
kilgree and i think i'm gonna go with
the skydiving because uh i think we've
just proven
very fun very fun so
that's what i think we're gonna do
man i'm gonna have to build an airplane
and then i'm gonna have to make loads of
rings for people to get through so
there's a few problems with this right
so what is to stop
somebody
skydiving off and just fly floating
really slowly
all the way through the hoops
and eventually lining it up so slowly
that they can't miss or you know i
okay i missed but you get my point
basically i'm gonna test it a million
times and i'm gonna say that you have to
complete your skydive within
four seconds three seconds however much
it is so if you float around and your
skydive lasts longer than that amount of
time disqualified zero points so there's
no point you have got to go fast you
have got to make it through and you
secure the most points by making it
through this ring at the bottom
so maybe someone else can have that idea
on the resistance team uh kill kill
impulse kill ren i think i think it's
there's legs on both ideas
so now i'm thinking this is actually the
perfect place for my mini game so i need
to go all the way up
to the build limit now
and i could probably do about three or
four hoops here after i build the
airplane but i'm also wondering
should we cut out or carve out a giant
square and make this go all the way to
bedrock and then have water at the
bottom
so there's even more craziness to this
minigame so you skydive down you gotta
go through the hoops through the hoops
and then plunge
to get your points so this is where we
need to build ourselves
an aeroplane but actually it's the most
insignificant part of the design the
main thing that needs to be done is all
of the rings so i need to figure out
what route people want to take because
if you're going down there's not
honestly not a lot of
variation you can do
so let's get into a small time lapse of
building
a very quick airplane actually
scratch that forget that we can't do a
time-lapse i haven't got any blocks
we need to go back to the base and get
some blocks and i think i can't even nab
some quartz from the barge because i
think all my stock's gone
someone keeps buying out all of this
quartz so there's a top priority for me
at the moment i mean actually speaking
of the barge i haven't had a look and
also
they've taken most of it they took the g
they took the g
we're gonna have to get that back at
some point i can't actually remember if
i said scar could have it or not but he
was being cheeky and i don't know where
it is now but we need to we'll have to
get that g backers i'm vanishing again
i'm a ghost
i'm gone but we have got some profits
elsewhere in the barge to pick up you
know i think next episode i'm gonna have
to do
i did some mining on camera 25 diamonds
not too shabby right let's go and get
our blocks for this airplane and in my
case
that doesn't mean grinding for it
manually no it means
consistently trading pumpkins and melons
until i have enough emeralds so i mean
we might do a little time-lapse of this
just so you understand how much trading
i have to do to get a small amount of
blocks all right let's go
just as i started that time lapse it was
very short i only did it for 20 minutes
but i accidentally
hit
villager number two
honestly i'm so devastated not really
because i lost a villager but because
it's such a pain
to move villagers around and to replace
him
i can't believe it so i mean this is
what happened look i got it i got a
recording of it evidence i just
accidentally when you right click these
guys it's very easy to press f and click
at the same time and that's
that's what happened and i've just
revealed that my inventory button is f
instead of e
weird i know and if you want to see what
the villagers point of view was look
this is how terrifying is this so we got
a loss but we do have a bunch of quartz
which is what we actually came over here
to do
so now we can actually do what we were
going to do the first time around which
is start building an airplane that you
can casually
fall out of
let's go
[Music]
vehicles are not my strong suit
including planes cars and tanks and
everything else
it's a miracle that i managed to make
even the body of the plane
and that's exactly why it has no wings
and it shouldn't be flying at all it's a
giant floating tic tac
but i have made the exits for it which
is probably why it looks a little bit
weird so
as you can see down there i've created
three rings and i've been thinking about
the design like i'm not gonna get this
gate oh great here we go let's go for it
it should be much easier
to nail a landing in there so here's
what i'm thinking i'm thinking that i
color code the different sizes of circle
and the harder the circle the more
points you get and then there'll be
multiple in the air but having done this
skydive now i feel like i'm definitely
going to have to
move everything to bedrock meaning a
whole lot of mining for me which i
definitely don't have time for
today so this this mini game probably
gonna take me a couple of episodes but i
still got like a week to make it and
perfect it and get it all looking good
so i'm pretty happy with how things have
gone so far let's do another little run
before we move on and do something else
before the end of the episode because
i've got a few things that i need to
take care of today so i could choose to
do this jump now there's obviously no
other rings but if i yeah it's so much
easier to nail even this half a block
space makes it so much easier so we'll
come back to the mini game of certain
death
in the next episode because i need to
take care of something at the barge ah
the barge my little baby barge you see
impulse moved his shop but added impulse
buys
here in the corner and while people have
been buying the odd thing or two
it's not ideal and people don't know
where to go for this stuff so i'm
thinking again going back to humble
beginnings
we're going to create a temporary very
small barge just so impulse buys has
somewhere to go for the time being this
is this is a bit of a throwback isn't it
this is how the barge started as just a
humble
little raft now the only reason that i'm
making a very small barge here for now
is simply because i'm not entirely sure
how i'm going to utilize all of this
space and expand upwards and outwards
just yet and i want to do impulse buys
well some justice i don't think it
deserves just being shoved in the corner
over there so just even a small thing
here would go a long way
now the art of the barge build
is actually not too much uniform so
you'll see i've put trapdoors all the
way around
and it looks like a crate it doesn't
look like a barge at all so the trick is
to replace some things and not others so
i will remove maybe 30 of these and
replace them with signs
and what this does is just breaks up the
barge and also no symmetry on this one
so you see how this is just too perfect
i'm actually going to replace some of
this out basically a full tutorial on
how to build
the barge
so you'll notice that some trap doors
are missing under and others aren't
and there we go it immediately looks a
lot better
and then of course we need to add a few
barrels
to actually store the stuff
it's a very temporary solution
but it will definitely help temporary
barge
restocked and ready to go with all of
the prismarine impulse buys now i like i
said this is temporary but barge current
partners present impulse buys it's
pretty simple now i do need to get all
of this sorted out i did say this
earlier didn't i see the problem is
basically
dress me up as a banana because i am
split that's my problem i am absolutely
my energy is split my attention is split
i am split between so many different
projects and things that i want to do
that i end up doing nothing at all so i
mean just call me the banana man now on
instagram there's an account called
hermitcraft quotes and
every time i say something that's a
little bit weird or a little bit off or
a little bit funny i wonder is it going
to make the quote wait
what if this makes the quote
it's quote-ception anyway i love
hermitcraft quotes so shout out to them
on instagram it's always a good laugh a
lot of the time it's things i don't even
remember saying right let's get rid of
all this stuff because we need our water
lake back
for
more barge expansion in the future i'm
also realizing that the barge is
becoming
so much more bigger not just physically
but also on the hermitcraft server like
people love going to the barge it's a
very convenient shop it has a lot of
stock and it is nearly always
stocked with what you need but i'm
realizing that the
the size of it is starting to get a bit
out of hand the scale has gone a bit
above and beyond
so
i've been thinking about after this
whole war thing is done i might need to
make a headquarters i might need to make
a storage facility and i certainly
certainly need to make my life a little
bit easier and get myself some stock
backlogged so i'm not constantly chasing
so next episode is probably going to be
a bit of a big one but like everything i
seem to be doing at the moment i'm going
to have to leave this a little bit half
finished that'll do for the time being
right i know it's a bit messy but you
know
banana man i'm split and speaking of
projects that never seem to get done
my goodness the mansion this is where
we're going to turn our attention to
after this war is all over the barge and
the mansion
are going to be our number one priority
there's a lot of things we need to do
but i am afraid that is all we have time
for today i'm actually gonna head over
to the upside down
so that i can afk for a million trillion
years
and end up with like three blocks of
gold because it's a very inefficient
farm so all there is left to say is
thank you very much watching don't
forget to check out the merch it is the
last day
it is the last day people last chance so
there's a link in the description anna
thank you very much for watching i'll
see you in the next episode good bye
[Music]